So, you want to get into Comfy Vi, but
there's just a problem or 10 problems or
20 problems.
Well, guys, let me be the first to tell
you that there can be many problems
getting into Comfy UI if you do not
configure it properly. So, I'm here to
show you how to do that correctly.
We will be using a service called
RunPod. And what they offer is a large
selection of GPUs that you can rent from
them and use to do a variety of things.
Whatever you think that you can do on a
GPU or whatever you've wanted to do on a
GPU, um, you know, 4090, 5090, just
don't have $5,000. Well, RunPod's got
you covered. And it's really, really
cheap. It's not free, unfortunately, but
it is cheap. So, we're going to head
over to runpod.com.
run pod.io, I guess. Um, and what you're
gonna have to do as soon as you get here
is sign up for an account and you're
going to want to configure a payment
method. Um, don't worry, you're not
going to be spending a ton of money.
It's like you can start out with $10 and
that'll ask you that'll last you like 20
hours. So, I'm going to sign in here.
You're going to sign up and as soon as
you do that, you should be on the
homepage here. So, this is the Run Pod
homepage and there is a lot here. It
might look a little intimidating, but
it's not. So, if you click on pods,
you're going to see a ton of GPUs here
with hourly prices on them. You can get
a RDX490, you can get an L40S, you can
get the H200, uh the 141 gigabyte VRAM
card, $40,000 card, you can get a 5090.
Um, they got a ton of cards here, but
um, the the ones that you're the ones
that most people are looking for are the
4090, the 5090, and maybe the H200 if
you're doing something like Laura
character creation for AI generation,
but that is a video for another day. Um,
starting out, you're just going to want
to get the RTX 4090. It's the staple
card. It can do anything that you're
going to want it to do. just getting
into things. So, grab the 4090. It's 50
cents an hour. It's really cheap. Pause
real quick, guys. Right back to the
video. But I do want to let you know, we
can both make money here. If you guys
use my referral link in the description,
you will get money and I will get money
for free. There's no downside to this,
guys. Come on, hook a brother up, do
yourself a salad, and uh let's get this
money. Back to the video.
The next thing you're going you're going
to want to do is come down to configure
development and you're going to see that
there is a pod template here. And this
is important. You're going to need to go
into the template and change it because
you're looking to run Comfy UI. And in
order to do that, you need to change the
template to have Comfy UI within your
pod. So, you're going to type in Comfy
UI
manager. Now, I just want to say if you
did get the 5090, which I don't know why
you did, but if you did, um you're going
to have to use a different configuration
here, and that is going to be this one
right here. You need PyTorch 2.8. Um if
you get the 5090, everybody who gets the
4090 though, um just starting out,
you're going to use this template right
here, Comfy Manager permanent disc.
Okay. And scrolling down here, we see
that there are some pricing options. And
you might be looking at that spot over
there and saying, "Oh, 29 cents an hour.
That's that's cheaper." Well, it's
interruptible, meaning if somebody wants
to pay 59 cents an hour and you have the
last one in your network, well, they're
going to kick you off and anything that
you're doing will just be, you know,
interrupted. So, just get the on demand,
get the 59 cent per hour uh card, and
that's that. Now, scrolling scrolling
down, we're almost to the bottom here,
but um there is a section called network
volume, and you want to configure this.
What this does basically is it gives you
a little little uh hard drive. So, the
hard drive space is whatever you select.
So, for example, I have 185 gigs here um
that's on a network in in the cloud that
I pay for. Now, it's not expensive, but
what this allows me to do is anytime
that I close Comfy UI, anything that I
save in Comfy UI will stay there. If you
do not configure this, everything that
you do will be deleted when you
terminate your pod. That means if you
install a bunch of 10 gigabyte models to
generate AI and you get everything set
up and you go, oh man, six hours later,
you're done. you got it all set up and
then you close your pod and you did not
do this, you will lose all of that time
and you'll have to do it again. So,
you're going to configure a network.
Just click create a network volume
and you're going to pick a region. Make
sure that you pick a region that has
cards. These should display regions that
have the 4090 because you clicked it
already. So, it it doesn't really matter
if you're in the United States and you
pick Europe. It's not going you're
you're going to have like maybe you know
90 millisecond latency. It's it's not a
big deal. You'll be fine. The size I
recommend starting off with like 100
gigabytes. You're not going to really be
downloading more than 100 gigabytes
worth of models or whatever you're doing
in your first go. And honestly, I'm at
185 gigs and I use this thing every day.
So, you really don't need that much. You
can manage the storage. You can delete
things from it. So, you know, pick a
100. It's going to charge you $7 a month
and I think it charges you daily. So
that means that you know if you want to
stop it at any point and or downsize or
upsize. You can do that. You can change
the size of it as you go. So you're
going to create the network volume. And
once you do that, you need to select it.
Make sure that you select it. If you do
not, you will screw yourself and you
will be very, very, very, very sorry.
It's not letting me select it because I
clicked 4090 and I guess there's not one
available in my region right now. So
anyway, you're going to want to just
click deploy on demand.
All right, now we've deployed our pod.
Um, it looks like some things are
loading here. And you might be saying,
what is what is all this? What the hell
is all this? So, this is a side tab
where you can see the logs of the
startup and you can basically just see
what's going on under the hood and this
will let you know when your Comfy UI and
your um Jupyter Labs are done
configuring and done set up. Mine is
already done because I've already used
this GPU on this network multiple times.
So, it's quick. But for you, this is
going to be about a 10 to 15 minute
process. It could be longer. I'm not
sure if it's network dependent, but I
think it is. So, um, go play with your
dog, go eat dinner, go annoy your
girlfriend or your wife, and, uh, come
back when that's done.
All right, welcome back. So, you will
know that everything is done when you
see down here in the logs tab, start
scripts finished. Pod is ready to go. So
that means that you are able to use
these ports to open up Jupyter Labs and
Comfy UI. But you can't open up Comfy UI
yet. There is one thing that you need to
do. You need to open up Jupyter Labs,
which is just a development environment
hosting site or application. And you're
going to
click the terminal down here. This is
just a terminal. I'm sure you've seen
one before. Um, it just opens up a
terminal within your web browser. All
you have to do to get Comfy UI going is
type bash space run_gpu.sh,
which initializes the the graphics card
that you just rented. So, we're going to
let that go. This should take
maybe two to three minutes for you on
your first startup. It might even take
me 2 to 3 minutes. So, I will see you
when that is done. Okay, it looks like
my Comfy is getting ready to start up
here. Um, you'll be able to tell that
your Comfy is ready to go when you start
seeing these fetches down here and it
says Comfy [music] Registry data 5 out
of whatever. Um, that means that you can
now launch Comfy UI. So, all you have to
do is come back to Run Pod and open up
Comfy UI. And there you go. You got it
running. Now, make sure that you drop a
subscription because I'm going to be
making videos on Comfy UI workflows,
making videos on models and what is the
best model to generate images, what is
the best model to generate videos and
all that good stuff. And I'm going to be
giving away to you guys for free.
And people charge hundreds of dollars
for this information. People are stingy
out here. There are gatekeepers. They do
not want you to know about this stuff
because you are competition to them. Um,
so if you are interested in knowing more
and getting your first workflow going
and you just want to keep this train
going, I will have videos out soon, but
you can join my Discord. The link is in
the description and I will help you out
there. I offer all types of support and
services and I have workflows for you
guys. I have all the models ready for
you guys. I will help you through
everything. Just hop in the Discord and
say what's up. Thank you guys for
watching. See you later.